Guide to the Ford Madox Ford collection, [ca. 1850]-1973
Ford, Ford Madox collection,
- Series IV. Photographs
  - Ford Madox Ford
    - Ford, Ford Madox, 1873-1939, [n.d.]; 21 photographs (Box 97, Folder 16)
      [Various photos at all ages; 1 caricature, some alone, most with Violet Hunt and others.]
    - Ford, Ford Madox, 1873-1939, [1920's?]; 1 photograph + 1 negative (Box 97, Folder 16.6)
    - Ford, Ford Madox, 1873-1939, [late 1920's]; 1 photograph (Box 97, Folder 16.7)
      [With unidentified man]
    - Ford, Ford Madox, 1873-1939, 1921; 3 photographs + 1 negative (Box 97, Folder 17)
      [Ford with Penny the goat at Coopers Cottage, Bedham. 1 photo, 2 copies, 1 negative]
    - Ford, Ford Madox, 1873-1939, 1935; 10 photographs + 1 magazine (Box 97, Folder 18)
      [Ford and Janice Biala - Photos, proofs and prints; plus "Rockefeller Center Weekly", Mar.14, 1935, p.3 has photo of Biala and Ford]
    - Ford, Ford Madox, 1873-1939, [1935?]; 1 photograph (Box 97, Folder 19)
      [With Janice Biala]
    - Ford, Ford Madox, 1873-1939, [193-?]; 5 photographs (Box 97, Folder 20)
      [5 proof photos of Ford done by Kaiden Studies, New York.]
    - Ford, Ford Madox, 1873-1939, [1930]; 2 photographs (Box 97, Folder 21)
      [2 copies of same photo]
    - Ford, Ford Madox, 1873-1939, [1930's]; 2 photographs (Box 97, Folder 22)
      [2 copies of same photo done by K.A. Porter]
    - Ford, Ford Madox, 1873-1939, 1932; 1 photograph (Box 97, Folder 23)
      [Ford and Ezra Pound in front of Columbus monument at Rapello, Italy]
    - Ford, Ford Madox, 1873-1939, Jun., 1938; 4 photographs (Box 97, Folder 24)
      [2 copies of Ford at the Olivet College commencement; 1 with Janice Biala; 1 with Joe Brewer]
    - Ford, Ford Madox, 1873-1939, [193-?]; 1 photograph (Box 97, Folder 25)
      [New York]
    - Ford, Ford Madox, 1873-1939, [1930/33?.]; 2 photograph + negative (Box 97, Folder 26)
      [Villa Paul, Toulon; Ford with Janice Biala and another woman, 2 copies]
    - Ford, Ford Madox, 1873-1939, [193-?]; 1 photograph (Box 97, Folder 27)
      [Ford at Villa Paul, Toulon]
    - Ford, Ford Madox, 1873-1939, 1937; 5 photographs (Box 97, Folder 28)
      [Clarksville, Tenn.; Ford and Caroline Tate, Alan Tate, Janice Biala, and George Marion O'Donnell at the Tate's house]
    - Ford, Ford Madox, 1873-1939, [193-'s.]; 7 photographs (Box 97, Folder 29)
      [6 secenes with Ford and Janice Biala; some in Olivet, some in Europe.]
    - Ford, Ford Madox, 1873-1939, [1925]; 1 photograph (Box 97, Folder 30)
      [Ford with Julie Hueffer at Cap Brun.]
    - Ford, Ford Madox, 1873-1939, [1935.]; 1 photograph (Box 97, Folder 30.5)
      [Ford with Janice Biala; inscribed to Julie from her father.]
    - Ford, Ford Madox, 1873-1939, [1930's]; 1 photograph (Box 97, Folder 31)
      [2 copies of Ford on the terrace of the Villa Paul, Toulon
    - Ford, Ford Madox, 1873-1939, [1896/1909]; 6 photographs + 2 leaves (Box 97, Folder 32)
      [Photographs of long strips of paper that hung inside the case of the gradfather clock in Ford and Elsie Hueffer's house throughout their marriage. It served as a sort of guest book.]
    - Ford, Ford Madox, 1873-1939, [1922?]; 1 photograph (Box 97, Folder 33)
      [4 copies of the pastel chalk drawing Stella Bowen drawed. Original in Mapcase B-7]]
  - G-Q
    - Garnett, David, 1892-1981, Jun.14, 1902; 1 photograph (Box 96, Folder 1)
      [Garnett with gentleman identified as Joseph Leopold but looks just like Ford. Printed photo taken from a book.]
    - Geary, W. N., [1827]; 2 photographs (Box 96, Folder 2)
      [One a portrait; one full view.]
    - Gillette, Wiliam, 1853-1937, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 96, Folder 3)
      [Gillette in costume]
    - Gladstone, Dora Bennett, [n.d.]; 1 photograph + envelope (Box 96, Folder 4)
      [Full portrait]
    - Glebe Cottage, Winchelsea, [190-?]; 1 photograph (Box 96, Folder 5)
    - Glyn, Elinor, 1864-1943, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 96, Folder 6)
      [Printed photo taken from pamphlet]
    - Goodwin, Ernest, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 96, Folder 7)
      [With Violet Hunt]
    - Gosse, Nelly, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 96, Folder 8)
    - Graham, Winifred (Mrs. Theodore Cory), d.1950, [n.d.]; 2 photographs (Box 96, Folder 9)
      [ 2 printed portraits, taken from magazine]
    - Greenwell, William, b.1820, [n.d.]; 2 photographs (Box 96, Folder 10)
      [Portraits, one cabinet card, signed. Once engaged to Margaret Raine (Hunt)]
    - Guilbert, Yvette, 1865-1944, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 96, Folder 11)
      [Cabinet card]
    - Dayang Muda of Sarawak, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 96, Folder 12)
      [Printed photo, with note by Violet Hunt]
    - Hardy, Thomas, 1840-1928, [n.d.]; 3 photographs (Box 96, Folder 13)
      [2 photos with 1 printed copy]
    - Hay, Lady Peggy, 1927; 2 photographs (Box 96, Folder 14)
    - Heath, Mrs., 1929; 1 photograph (Box 96, Folder 15)
    - Hodgson, Mrs., [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 96, Folder 16)
    - Hook, James Clarke, 1819-1907, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 96, Folder 17)
    - Howard, Henry FitzAlan, Duke of Norfolk, 1847-1917, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 96, Folder 18)
      [Printed photo]
    - Howell, Rev. Alexander, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 96, Folder 19)
      [Photo of sketch ofVicar of Darlington in the pulpet.]
    - Hueffer, Catherine Brown, 1850-1927, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 96, Folder 20)
      [Ford's grandmother]
    - Hueffer, Elsie Martindale, 1827-1949, [1920's]; 6 photographs (Box 96, Folder 21)
      [4 of Elsie; 2 of homes]
    - Hueffer, Elsie Martindale, 1827-1949, [1917?].]; 3 photographs (Box 96, Folder 22)
      [2 of Elsie and Katherine; 1 of home at Charing during WWI]
    - Hueffer, Elsie Martindale, 1827-1949, 1908; 1 photograph (Box 96, Folder 23)
    - Hueffer, Elsie Martindale, 1827-1949, [1905?]; 2 photographs (Box 96, Folder 24)
      [2 poses at Cologne Cathedral]
    - Hueffer, Elsie Martindale, 1827-1949, [1903?.]; 1 photograph (Box 96, Folder 25)
      [With Katherine and Christina]
    - Hueffer, Elsie Martindale, 1827-1949, [n.d.]; 4 photographs (Box 96, Folder 26)
      [Elsie as a young girl and woman; one cabinet card]
    - Hueffer, Elsie Martindale, 1827-1949, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 96, Folder 27)
      [Elsie and her brother Harri[son] at Glebe Cottage, Winchelsea.]
    - Hueffer, Elsie Martindale, 1827-1949, [n.d.]; 5 photographs (Box 96, Folder 28)
      [At Aldington; home scenes, 1 with Elsie]
    - Hueffer, Katherine, [n.d.]; 2 photographs (Box 96, Folder 29)
      [Katherine (Babs) as a young girl]
    - Hueffer, Oliver, 1877-1931, [1917]; 1 photograph (Box 96, Folder 30)
      [Ford's brother]
    - Hunt, Alfred William, 1830-1896, [n.d.]; 2 photographs (Box 96, Folder 31)
      [Violet's father. 1 printed photo; 1 locket size, faded but thought to be Hunt]
    - Hunt, Alfred William, 1830-1896, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 96, Folder 32.5)
      [Violet's father. Cabinet card with negative]
    - Hunt, Margaret, Raine, 1831-1912, [n.d.]; 3 photographs (Box 96, Folder 33)
      [Violet's mother. 2 cabinet cards; 1 printed]
    - Hunt, Sarah (Mrs. Andrew), [n.d.]; 4 photographs (Box 96, Folder 34)
      [Alfred William Hunt's mother.1 cabinet card with copy; 1 albumen print with copy]
    - Hunt, Violet, 1862-1942, [n.d.]; 88 photographs (Box 96, Folder 35)
      [Photos of all ages; many with friends & relatives; some home photos at South Lodge.]
    - Hunt, Violet, 1862-1942, [1882?]; 1 photograph (Box 96, Folder 36)
      [Violet in her late teens or early twenties]
    - Hunt, William Holman, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 96, Folder 37)
    - Huxley, Julian, 1887-1975, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 96, Folder 38)
    - Irving, Henry, 1838-1905, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 1)
    - Jackson, Nell, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 2)
    - James, Henry, 1843-1916, 1907; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 3)
      [Printed photo inscribed to Violet Hunt]
    - Janotha, Maria, 1856-1932, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 4)
      [Printed photo, cut from magazine]
    - Laing, Theresa, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 5)
      [Cabinet card; cousin of Margaret Raine Hunt, Violet's mother]
    - Lamb, Katherine Hueffer, 1963; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 6)
      [With Rosemary Mizener and husband Charles]
    - Miscellaneous Landscapes, [n.d.]; 8 photographd+ 1 sketch (Box 98, Folder 7)
      [4 on postcards; 2 from California, 1 castle, sketch of Brignal Banks]
    - Lang, Andrew, 1844-1912, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 8)
      [Reproduction of portrait]
    - Linch, Letty, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 9)
      [Cabinet card of Linch in costume]
    - Lindsay, Dr. Alexander of Pinkieburn, ca. 1890., [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 10)
      [Photo of portrait by Sir Henry Raeburn; on postcard]
    - Liszt, Franz, 1811-1866, Jan.31, 1883; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 10.3)
      [Cabinet card inscribed to Frances Hueffer by Liszt.]
    - Loewe, Esther Julia Madox, 1920-1985, [late 1920's]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 10.5)
    - Loewe, Esther Julia Madox, 1920-1985, [1927?]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 10.7)
      [4 pastel colored prints and 4 negatives of Julie drawed by Stella Bowen.Original in Mapcase B-7.]
    - MacKenzie, Sir Compton, 1883-1972, Jul.10, 1919; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 11)
      [Printed caricature byBohun Lynch]
    - McGregor, Andrew, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 12)
      [Cabinet card. Married Alfred William Hunt's sister Sarah.]
    - MacColl, Dugland Sutherland, 1859-1948, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 13)
    - Martindale, Harrison, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 14)
      [Brother of Elsie Martindale Hueffer]
    - Martindale, Mary, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 15)
      [Sister of Elsie Martindael Hueffer]
    - Martindale, Mary, [n.d.]; 4 photographs (Box 98, Folder 16)
      [2 with Violet Hunt; 2 copies of one]
    - Martindale, Dr. William, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 17)
      [Father of Elsie Martindale Hueffer]
    - Martindale, Mrs. William, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 18)
      [Mother of Elsie Martindale Hueffer]
    - Marwood, George, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 19)
      [1 with Elsie at Aldington]
    - Masterman, Lucy, 1884-1977, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 20)
    - Morris, Mrs. William, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 21)
      [At Kelmscott]
    - Neilson, Julia, 1868-1957, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 22)
      [Printed photo; in costume]
    - Newcombe, C. T., [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 23)
    - Patmore, Brigit, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 24)
      [Taken by Cecil Beaton]
    - Peacock, Mrs. & Mr., [n.d.]; 8 photographs + envelope (Box 98, Folder 25)
      [4 copies of each of 2 photos; identifies subjects as Thomas Peacock's grandparents]
    - Plowden, Edidtha, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 26)
      [London; Cabinet card; School friend of Violet Hunt]
    - Prinsep, Valentine Cameron, 1838-1904, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 27)
    - Quinn, John, Nov.23, 1906; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 28)
      [New York; 1 photograph of the foyer of Constantin Braucusi]
  - R-Z
    - Reynolds, Stephen, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 29)
    - Routledge, Mary Pattinson, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 30)
      [Cabinet card. Friend of Margaret Raine Hunt; wife of the Publisher]
    - Ross, Dennison, 1923; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 31)
    - Rossetti, Christiana Georgina, 1830-1894, [n.d.]; 2 photographs (Box 98, Folder 32)
      [2 copies of same printed photo]
    - Rossetti, Dante Gabriel, 1828-1882, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 33)
      [Photo of oil painting of Rossetti done by William Holman Hunt]
    - Rossetti, William Michael, 1829-1919, [n.d.]; 2 photographs (Box 98, Folder 34)
    - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 35)
    - Ruskin, Mrs. John, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 36)
    - Scholsper, Maud, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 37)
      [Cabinet card. School friend of Violet Hunt]
    - Shiekland, Enty, 1887/88; 2 photographs (Box 98, Folder 38)
      [Two cabinet cards]
    - Sitwell, Sir Osbert, 5th Baronet, 1892-1969, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 39)
    - Sitwell, Sir Osbert, 5th Baronet, 1892-1969, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 40)
    - Sitwell, Sir Osbert, 5th Baronet, 1892-1969, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 41)
      [With Richard Aldington]
    - Skuit, Molly, Nov.16, 1886; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 42)
      [School friend of Violet Hunt]
    - Sladen, Douglas, 1856-1947, [1914]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 43)
      [On postcard; signed]
    - Smally, Eleanor, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 44)
    - Soskice, Juliet M. Hueffer, d.1944, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 45)
      [Cabinet card. As a child]
    - South Lodge, [1914?]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 46)
    - Storkhausen, Baroness von, 1781-1855, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 47)
      [Cabinet card. Translator of Margaret Raine Hunt's stories]
    - Terry, Ellen, 1848-1928, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 48)
      [Actress]
    - Terry, Kate, 1844-1924, [n.d.]; 3 photographs (Box 98, Folder 49)
      [Printed photos]
    - Van der Noot, Edmee, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 50)
      [With H. G. Wells; Hueffer girls' governess]
    - Unidentified, 1925; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 50.5)
      [Inscribed to Ford and Stella [Bowen]]
    - Unknown persons, [n.d.]; 15 photographs (Box 98, Folder 51)
      [Various places. 6 cabinet cards, 1 printed photo]
    - Walpole, Sir Hugh Seymour, 1884-1941, Jul.10, 1919; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 52)
      [Caricature by Bohun Lynch]
    - Was, Henrietta Mary Ada, 1832-1924, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 53)
    - Ware, Mrs., [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 54)
    - Watts, Alaric A., 1797-1864, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 55)
    - Wells, Augusta, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 56)
      [Sister of H. G. Wells]
    - Wells, George Philip, 1901-1985, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 57)
    - Wells, H[erbert] G[eorge], 1866-1946, [1920?]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 58)
      [With Brigit Patmore]
    - Wells, H[erbert] G[eorge], 1866-1946, [1905?.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 59)
      [With Edmee Van der Noot, Hueffer girls' governess]
    - Wells, H[erbert] G[eorge], 1866-1946, [n.d.]; 1 photograph (Box 98, Folder 60)
    - Wentworth, Sophie, [n.d.]; 2 photographs (Box 98, Folder 61)
      [1 cabinet card; School friend of Violet Hunt; at different ages]
    - West, Rebecca, 1892-1983, [n.d.]; 3 photographs (Box 98, Folder 62)
      [2 with Ford; 1 with Ford and Violet Hunt]
    - Wolmark, A., 1927; 2 photographs + negative (Box 98, Folder 63)
      [Photo of sketch of Ford by Wolmark]
    - Wright, Renee, [n.d.]; 5 photographs (Box 98, Folder 64)
      [Allegedly the "Ford's woman" after Stella Bowen]
  - Photograph album
    - Loewe, Esther Julia Madox, 1920-1985 D Photographic Album, 1921-1936; 37 leaves (Box 99, Folder 1)
      [Photos from infancy to 1936; taken in France, Scotland, England, and elsewhere as she travelled with mother, Stella Bowen and father, Ford]
      Link to the guide containing descriptions of the individual photos within the album. PDF File
- Series V. Clippings
  - Bowen, Stella M [Printed ], 1923-42; 17 items (Box 100, Folder 1)
    [Clippings about Bowen and her life as an artist.]
  - Ford, Ford Madox M[Printed], 1926-29; 48 items (Box 100, Folder 2)
    [Clippings about Ford, his life and his books.]
  - Ford, Ford Madox M[Printed], 1916-17; 81 items (Box 100, Folder 3)
  - Ford, Ford Madox M[Printed], 1930-39; 48 items (Box 100, Folder 4)
  - Ford, Ford Madox M[Printed], 1946-72; 9 items (Box 100, Folder 5)
  - Bowen, Stella M [Printed, copies], 1923-42; 17 items (Box 101, Folder 1)
    [Photocopies of clippings about Bowen and her life as an artist, as in box 100]
  - Ford, Ford Madox M[Printed, copies], 1916-17; 81 items (Box 101, Folder 2)
    [Photocopies of clippings about Ford, his life and his books, as in box 100.]
  - Ford, Ford Madox M[Printed, copies], 1916-17; 81 items (Box 101, Folder 3)
  - Ford, Ford Madox M[Printed, copies], 1930-39; 48 items (Box 101, Folder 4)
  - Ford, Ford Madox M[Printed,copies], 1946-72; 9 items (Box 101, Folder 5)
- Series VI. Literary Portraits
  - Ford, Ford Madox M[Printed] Literary Portraits, 1913-1915; 300+ leaves (Box 102, Folder 1)
    [Photocopies of "Literary Portraits" from the issues of The Outlook, Sept. 13, 1913 - June 26, 1915; London.]
  - Ford, Ford Madox M[Printed] Literary Portraits, 1907-1908; 100+ leaves (Box 102, Folder 2)
    [Photocopies of "Literary Portraits" from the issues of The London Tribune, July 27, 1907 - January 25, 1908.]
  - Ford, Ford Madox M[Printed] Literary Portraits, 1907; 50+ leaves (Box 102, Folder 3)
    [Photocopies of "Literary Portraits" from the issues of The Daily Mail, April 20-July 20, 1907; London.]
- Series VII. The Saddest Story
  - Mizener, Arthur TM[copy] "The Saddest Story"- Typescript, [1970?]; 3,000+ leaves (Box 103, Folder 4)
    [Photocopies of "The Saddest Story, much like boxes 86 and 87.]
SEPARATED MATERIAL
Bound Manuscripts - cataloged individually in the Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections
Bd. Ms. 1 Ford Madox Ford and the Arts, Summer, 1989. Named "Contemp. Lit.": Galley proofs of an Issue of "Contemporary Literature" v.30, no.2; Devoted to Ford, guest editor: Joseph Wiesenfarth.
Bd. Ms 2-3+ That Same Poor Man, Circa 1928. Names Croyd I & II: Bound typed manuscript by Ford, with corrections in holograph of "That Same Poor Man", in 2 volumes, in slip case.
Bd. Ms. 4 Souvenir: Anecdote et pensee diverse ou morale de l'histoire et des pholosophe,1770. Named Diary: In unknown hand, French volume of 690 pages [pages 682-689 missing] of happenings, thoughts and philosophy in the 1770's. Arranged alphabetically, with main titles in the margins.
Bd. Ms 5 English Country or Gringoire s'en va-t-en Guerre: A Reconstructionary Tale, Circa 1927. >Named English Country: Typed manuscript by Ford of an unpublished story, thought to be renamed "No Enemy" when published. Signed by Ford on title page. In slipcase.
Bd. Ms. 6+ The Last Sowing: a Romance, 1895-1898. Named Last: Early work of Ford; first portion is in the hand of Elsie Hueffer, Ford's own hand is after p.333.
Bd. Ms. 7 The Marsden Case, Circa 1922. Named Marsden: Hand written and typed manuscript by Ford, with holographic corrections. In case, within slip case.
Bd. Ms. 8+ O Hymen, 1927. Named O Hymen: Typed manuscript by Ford, with a few holographic corrections. In slip case.
Bd. Ms. 9 The Rash Act, 1933. Named Rash: In Ford's hand, bound manuscript. In slip case.
Bd. Ms. 10++ Literary Cuttings, 1908-1909. Newspaper clippings with reviews of articles and poems from the "English Review", edited by Ford.
Bd. Ms. 11+ The Saddest Story, Circa 1914-1915. Photocopy of the manuscript of Ford's "The Saddest Story". In case.
Bd. Ms. 12+ W.H. Hudson "Some Reminiscences", Circa 1935. In Ford's hand, essay on W. H. Hudson, author, naturalist and ornithologist.